yogile.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy - Easy photo sharing | Yogile

  * General
  * Data Policies
  * Your Data And Export
  * Data Removal / Changes & Tracking Removal

Effective date: 23 May 2018 

At Yogile we're committed to your privacy. In this privacy section, we offer transparency on how and why we process your data, and give you the tools to control it. 

Browse through the 'Data Policies' tab to get more information about your personal data and how it is used. If you have an account, make sure you're logged in first; this will allow you to perform many actions by yourself without needing to contact us. 

**General points:**

  * You can inspect and export the personal data and information that we have collected on you, by visiting the 'Your Data and Export' section. If your data or information is incorrect, you can request to amend it. For specific details see each section in 'Data Policies'.
  * Your personal data is never used in automated decision making or profiling.
  * We never sell or trade your personal data to outside parties.
  * Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 16 years of age or older. We will delete any personal information as soon as possible once we have learned that this information is from a person under the age of 16.
  * We may release your information when it is necessary to comply with the law.
  * Your personal data is handled and protected with the greatest possible care. We try to keep the amount of personal data we need from you as minimal as possible; we only ask you for the information necessary to provide you with our services at Yogile. In doing so, we comply with the requirements of several privacy laws including GDPR. We provide these privacy features to all of our users worldwide.
  * Everything in this Privacy Policy applies to the website as well as the mobile apps.

In case you have more questions after going through our Data Policies, you can contact us here. 

Click on each section to get detailed information. All network communication between you and the website or other mobile apps is always protected by a secure connection (SSL). 

Your Photos

**Purpose of data processing:** | To safely store and organize your photos.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | The photo image and metadata, which may contain EXIF, GPS location data and shot date. The IP address and user account that the photo was uploaded from.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Everyone who uploads a photo to Yogile.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | For users with a free account (including users with or without an account), a maximum of 8 days. For users with a paid account, photos are kept for as long as you're subscribed to the account. In addition, paid users get a double backup of their photos, so we can recover them in case you accidently remove photos, or require a disaster recovery. Double backups are kept for a maximum of 6 months, after which they are removed. If you have a paid account and it expires, it becomes a free account and your photos will be automatically removed 8 days later.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | Albums can be removed when you're logged in, by hovering over the album thumbnail and clicking the trash can icon. Photos can be removed by selecting or clicking on them, then clicking the 'delete' button. If you uploaded photos without an account, you can request removal using the [Photo removal page here](https://www.yogile.com/feedback/dmca). Data cannot be removed from double backups before their 6 month expiration, for technical reasons. In case of a (disaster) recovery from the double backup, we have the necessary procedures in place to make sure that photos from users that were removed or requested to be removed, are not restored from the double backup.  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | The credentials to access your photos and double backups are only available to the data protection person. Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Backblaze in Amazon Web Services (AWS) have their own necessary security procedures in place to ensure safe storage and access. In addition, you can change the privacy settings of each album, making sure they are only accessible by you, even if you accidently share an album url with others.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | Photos are stored on Amazon Web Services (AWS) S3 and the double backups on Backblaze B2.  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * AWS USA. GDPR compliance at <https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/gdpr-center>
  * BackBlaze USA. GDPR compliance at <https://help.backblaze.com/hc/en-us/sections/360000902933-GDPR-General-Data-Protection-Regulation->

User Account And Related Data

**Purpose of data processing:** | To organize photos under your account. If you upload a photo into someone else's album, when logged in, they are able to filter the photos according to who uploaded it, using the 'Display Name' you chose.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | Email, current IP address, account 'Display Name', timestamp of last login, timestamp of last request and metadata on how you organized photos in your account in albums, folders and favorites.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Everyone that has signed up for an account on Yogile.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | For as long as you have your account and keep it active during a period of 2 years. If you haven’t used your account in more than 2 years, your account and all related data and photos will be removed automatically.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | You first need to log in to your account. You can then [visit the My Profile Page](https://www.yogile.com/account) and update your details. To remove your account and related data [visit the Account Removal page](https://www.yogile.com/unregister).  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | The data is stored in the database on our web-server (hosted by Vultr). The server and database are only accessible with an encryption key that only our data protection person holds.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | This data is stored and collected on a server rented from Vultr USA  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

Backups of User Account And Related Data

**Purpose of data processing:** | To restore the latest copy of the 'User Account and Related Data' for the purpose of disaster recovery or in case of a server malfunction.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | Same as for section 'User Account and Related Data': Email, current IP address, account 'Display Name', timestamp of last login, timestamp of last request and metadata on how you organized photos in your account in albums, folders and favorites.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Everyone that has signed up for an account on Yogile.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | Backups that are more than 6 months old are automatically removed.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | No changes are possible because of legal and disaster recovery requirements. However, in case of a (disaster) recovery from the backup, we have the necessary procedures in place to make sure that data from users that was removed or requested to be removed, is not restored from the backup.  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | Backups are always encrypted. First they are put on our web-server (hosted by Vultr), after which they are encrypted and backed-up with our storage provider Amazon Web Services (AWS). Only the data protection person has access to and can unencrypt these backups.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | Backups are transferred to Amazon Web Services (AWS) after being created on a server rented from Vultr USA.  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * AWS USA. GDPR compliance at <https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/gdpr-center>
  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

Account Related E-mails

**Purpose of data processing:** | To inform you about the trial account expiration and to send other account related e-mails. In addition, we send you a notification when someone uploads a photo into one of your albums.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | E-mail.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Everyone who signs up for an account on Yogile.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | For as long as you have your account and keep it active during a period of 2 years. If you haven’t used your account in more than 2 years, your account and all related mailings will be removed automatically.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | You first need to log in to your account. You can then [visit the My Profile Page](https://www.yogile.com/account) and update your e-mail address. You cannot unsubscribe from account related e-mails like the trial expiration. To disable e-mail notifications when someone uploads a photo into one of your albums, [visit the 'My Profile Page'](https://www.yogile.com/account), and uncheck 'Send notification when someone adds photos to my albums'.  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | This data is stored in the database on our web-server (hosted by Vultr). The server and database are only accessible with an encryption key, which is held by our data protection person.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | This data is stored and collected on a server rented from Vultr USA. E-mails are sent using a 3rd party e-mail sending provider, AuthSMTP EU  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

Payment Data

**Purpose of data processing:** | To pay for a premium account—which gives you extra features like unlimited photo storage—record your payment receipts, and comply with local tax laws.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | Credit Card number, expiration date, country paid from, payment amount and timestamp.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Anyone upgrading to a premium Yogile account.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | 8 years.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | Payment data cannot be removed, as it is needed to comply with tax laws. Payment history can be found under [My Profile](https://www.yogile.com/account) once you're logged in.  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | Your full credit-card number is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology directly to our Payment gateway provider Stripe, without touching our servers. Stripe has the necessary procedures in place to keep all of your payment information confidential. In case you have subscribed to the premium plan using an in-app-purchase from the iOS Yogile app, you data is secured by Apple's payment mechanisms, and your personal payment data does not touch our servers.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | Stripe USA. Apple USA. In the case of a tax audit on our business, we may have to provide payment details to the Dutch tax authorities.  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * Stripe USA. GDPR compliance at <https://stripe.com/guides/general-data-protection-regulation#stripe-and-the-gdpr>
  * Apple USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/governance> and <https://www.apple.com/privacy>.

Facebook Login

**Purpose of data processing:** | To make it easier for you to login, without needing to use a separate e-mail and password.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | Only your e-mail address. We don't link or use any other details from your Facebook account, such as your name.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Everyone that uses the login with Facebook option on the website or app.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | For as long as you have your account and keep it active during a period of 2 years. If you haven’t used your account in more than 2 years, your account and all related data and photos will be removed automatically.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | You first need to log in to your account. You can then [visit the My Profile Page](https://www.yogile.com/account) and update your details. To remove your account and related data [visit the Account Removal page](https://www.yogile.com/unregister).  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | This data is stored in the database on our web-server (hosted by Vultr). The server and database are only accessible with an encryption key, which is held by our data protection person.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | This data is stored and collected on a server rented from Vultr USA  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

Website Traffic Logs

**Purpose of data processing:** | Troubleshooting in case of application errors, investigating security incidents and to comply with the law.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | IP address, timestamp of request, web page on Yogile accessed.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Every visitor to the Yogile website or app.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | A maximum of 1 year.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | No changes are possible because of legal and security requirements.  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | Website traffic logs are collected on our web-server (hosted by Vultr) and rolled-over daily, after which they are encrypted and backed-up with our storage provider Amazon Web Services (AWS). Only the data protection person has access to and can unencrypt these logs.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | Transferred to Amazon Web Services (AWS) and collected on a server rented from Vultr USA.  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * AWS USA. GDPR compliance at <https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/gdpr-center>
  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

Contact/Feedback Form Data And DMCA/Photo Removal Requests

**Purpose of data processing:** | To respond to your customer service requests and support needs. In addition we also need them to resolve DMCA/Photo Removal requests. Yogile needs the data to prove compliance regarding requests to remove content from our service.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | In the case of customer support via the feedback form, your e-mail address and contact message. In the case of DMCA/Photo Removal requests, your e-mail, name, IP address, the contents of the request and timestamp of the request.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Anyone who uses the feedback form for customer support, or the DMCA/Photo Removal form.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | For DMCA requests, 3 years, as we need them to prove compliance. All other support requests will be kept for 6 months.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | This data will be automatically removed once the retention period expires, but cannot be removed before that for compliance reasons.  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | The data is stored in the database on our web-server (hosted by Vultr). The server and database are only accessible with an encryption key, which is held by our data protection person.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | This data is stored and collected on a server rented from Vultr USA  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

Analytics Tracking

**Purpose of data processing:** | To gather statistics on key-metrics regarding the Yogile website, such as bounce rates, amount of visitors, traffic sources, etc.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | Anonymized IP address.  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Everyone that visits the Yogile website.  
**How long will this data be kept:** | 14 months.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | Visit the remove tracking page to remove yourself from the 3rd party web analytics tracking service Google Analytics (GA).  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | We have enabled anonymized IP address tracking, minimized data retention settings in Google Analytics, disabled 'Remarketing' and 'Advertising Reporting Features' in Google Analytics, minimizing the amount of tracking data stored and processed.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | Google Analytics USA  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | Google Analytics USA. GDPR compliance at <https://privacy.google.com/businesses/compliance>  
  
Cookies

**Purpose of data processing:** | We use first-party session cookies to maintain your account session once you've logged in. We also use a cookie to store which photos you have uploaded anonymously. Through this, you are still able to delete a photo even if you're anonymous by using the same device you uploaded it from. Additionally, we use cookies to store your preferences in regard to how you want to see albums, sort them and more. Our payment provider Stripe uses cookies so you don't have to re-enter your account e-mail when you make a payment. Facebook stores a cookie so that you don't have to re-login to your Facebook Account when you decide to share your album or photos with others directly on Facebook.  
---|---  
**Types of personal data processed:** | Cookie  
**Who is this data collected from:** | Anyone who visits the Yogile website  
**How long will this data be kept:** | Cookies have a default lifetime of 4 years.  
**How to delete/modify this data:** | To disable or remove cookies (for Yogile or other sites), please visit this link: <https://cookies.insites.com/disable-cookies>  
**What security measures are there to protect this personal data:** | All cookies from Yogile are encrypted.  
**This data is transferred to these 3rd parties:** | This data is processed on a server rented from Vultr USA  
**Which of these 3rd parties are located outside the EU:** | 

  * Vultr USA. GDPR compliance at <https://www.vultr.com/faq/#accordion-gdpr>

In case you have more questions after going through our data policies, you can contact us here.  
The company controlling data on Yogile is Monon B.V. registered at Lutmastraat 1 3, 1072 JL Amsterdam, the Netherlands. 

If you have an account, please log in first to export/see your data. If you don't have an account, use the contact form and send us the share url of the photo or album you want the data for.

## User Account

If you have an account, log in first to remove the data yourself. If not, you can use the Photo Removal form, and mention the account, photo or album you want to remove.

## 3rd Party Tracking

Visit the remove tracking page to remove yourself from the 3rd party web analytics tracking service Google Analytics.
